Now in this video,
I'm just going to
give you a very
basic rundown of how
this works. And then
in the next few,
we're going to do
some work and I'm
going to give you
step -by -step process
to follow to build
your video strategy, which
is exciting, right? Hopefully
you're excited, not scared.
Okay, so to start,
let's just look at
why research matters so
much. Okay, so I
need to have a
serious word with you
about this because you
are going to do
this, but I can
guarantee you will fail
if you sit here
and go, I'm going
to make this video
because I think it's
a good idea based
on nothing other than
what you think is
a good idea. However,
if you do what
I'm going to show
you, you're going to
get results like this.
Now, every answer view
is going to want
to make the idea
you think is a
good idea, but please
never do this. We
always have to make
ideas and videos based
on the data that
we find on YouTube
and on our own
channels. If we don't
do that, it's game
over. So in a
second, I'm going to
show you how we
got 450 ,000 subscribers
on our channel in
18 months. Using this
very simple system. But
putting it simply, the
research process we do
reveals what your viewers
like and they want,
and it tells you
what they don't want.
And the way that
we find out what
they like is by
analyzing outliers. So an
outlier is a video
on your channel or
someone else's channel that
noticeably grew it faster.
And when we find
that, it's potentially a
sign of what our
viewers want. So we
then go through the
process I'm going to
show you in the
other videos to pull
it apart and discover
what we take from
that and then apply
to our own to
hopefully get more views.
So let's use this
channel as an example.
We are going to
find an outlier on
it. And the first
thing we do is
look and go, what's
the average views on
this channel? I don't
get a calculator out.
I don't need any
software. I just go,
okay, about 200 ,000.
And then I scroll
down and I'm going
to look for videos
that have maybe got
over 400 ,000 views,
which would be a
2x outlier. And I
scroll down and I
see this one 700
,000 views. Boom. As
we can see, it's
ignoring almost every single
rule I've taught you
about how to make
thumbnails. Titles. It's cluttered.
The title's weird. The
face is odd. But
that's YouTube. Sometimes things
don't make sense. So
I would look at
that and go, right,
we need to watch
this. We need to
look at the comments.
We need to do
everything I'm going to
show you how to
do. And we need
to find out what
worked in that and
ask ourselves, do we
apply it to our
own channel? And that's
the basics of finding
an outlier. It's as
simple as that. Now,
having said that an
outlier is probably more
than 2x the average
video views of the
channel, if you find
a channel and the
average views are 300
,000, you're probably going
to find one with
600 ,000 views. There's
not an outlier. It
needs to be a
lot of views for
the niche, not just
the individual channel. But
also what can happen
is sometimes we find
channels that are getting
a million views per
video and you might
look and go, well,
it's only got 2
million views. So it's
only a 2x outlier.
That's still a huge
amount of views. So
we've got to use
our common sense here.
But what we need
to always do is
find outliers and then
analyze the patterns. We
do not want to
analyze patterns and copy
what didn't work on
videos that were below
average performers because that's
just dumb. Why would
we do that? So
an outlier just has
high views for the
niche and it basically
shows us what our
buyers might love to
watch. So now I'm
going to show you
how we use outliers
to grow a channel.
And this is the
very basics of it.
So we look for
outliers on our channel.
We then look for
outliers in the niche.
And then we look
for kind of outliers
in the general audience.
And then we look
for outliers in the
general audience. And then
we analyze the patterns
within those outliers and
we apply it to
our channel. And what
happens is when we
take what works from
our own channel, the
niche, and kind of
the wider YouTube space,
we end up with
this sweet spot here.
This sweet spot here
is what differentiates you.
And this is really
important because most people
in your niche are
going to research the
niche and they're going
to apply what worked
for everyone else in
your niche, which as
you're about to find
out often doesn't work,
but doesn't make you
look original. And originality
is really key. Like
we have to make
you differentiate. So this
is where the glory
is on YouTube and
working out how to
apply it here as
well as making sure
you take what works
from this. So all
we do is we
find what works, we
harness the patterns, and
then we differentiate. And
let me give you
a rundown now of
how we did this
on Living Leggings to
go from 25 ,000
to 450 ,000 subscribers
in 18 months. So
the first thing we
do is we look
at the patterns on
our own channel. Now,
you might fall into
this same problem we
did in that Liv's
channel back then just
had yoga tutorials on
it and we couldn't
really find any patterns.
It just felt really
random as to what
did well and what
didn't. So we actually
learned nothing from her
channel, which she'd been
posting to for like,
I don't know, a
year or so before
we started working on
it. And then we
just moved on. And
that's fine. If you
don't find any patterns
on your channel, don't
worry about it. Then
we moved into the
niche. So we started
looking at other yoga
channels and we came
across this one, Yoga
With Adrian. Millions of
views. And what we
noticed was there was
almost no real patterns
on her channel either.
The thumbnails sucked. She
was just making these
tutorials that felt like
potluck. And then when
we kept looking at
the rest of the
niche, it was the
same story. Everyone was
copying this one channel.
Bad thumbnails, same strategy,
really sporadic views. Nothing
really made that much
sense. Everything went against
what I'm going to
teach you now. So
we moved on to
the adjacent niche, the
kind of wider niches.
So an adjacent niche
would be. If you're
a guitar channel, you
then study outliers in
the drum and the
trumpet channel. If you're
a yoga, you look
at mobility and weights.
If you're tax, you'd
be accounting and business.
There's no set right
or wrong for this.
You just use your
common sense and go,
what's a similar kind
of niche? And this
is where you are
going to find all
the results. Most of
you are going to
research your niche, doing
what I've told you
and go, oh, my
gosh, there's nothing here
for me to learn
from. And then you're
going to panic and
go, what do I
do, Ed? And I'm
going to say, don't
worry, because most of
the results are going
to come from the
adjacent niches and working
out how to apply
them. So let me
show you what I
mean. We go into
the mobility space. I
live channel. Can we
notice something? Look how
simple these thumbnails are.
And also look how
short these videos are.
All the videos in
the yoga niche should
be like twenty five
minutes and the lessons.
This guy is giving
bingeable quick tips that
are short with really
simple thumbnails and short
kind of clickbait titles.
And then there's Jeff
Nippard here doing weightlifting
stuff, getting millions and
millions of views. We
thought, well, what if
we took what worked
for them and applied
it to our niche?
Bosh. And here's the
result. Eight million views.
So what you can
see here is the
thumbnail style. We noticed
a pattern.
We saw the
And then we just
had a lighter background
because that's what we
had to shoot up
against. And if you
look here, you can
see this is the
old strategy. Now, these
videos have got way
more views than they
did because the channel
blew up. But the
first one in the
new strategy got two
point four million views.
This one got eight.
This one got one
point six. This one
got one point two.
So that only happened
because our niche sucked
and our channel sucks.
And we just looked
a bit wider to
see what works and
applied it to our
own niche. And as
you can see, the
views are insane. But
also what I need
to point out is
I've been telling you
for ages, repeat what
works, repeat what works.
This channel is one
of the best examples
of it. Look how
similar these thumbnails are.
We just found that
the comparison strategy works.
So we just kept
using it and it
kept working to the
point where I remember
watching the video and
I was like, oh,
this is a good
idea. But one day
Liv was getting frustrated
because she wanted to
come up with a
thumbnail for a video
and she was trying
all these new styles.
I was like, Liv,
just use one that
already worked and change
the color of your
outfit and change the
days. And hey, presto,
three hundred thousand views.
And we discover this
by looking at the
niche, testing patterns from
the niche on our
channel, looking at the
adjacent niche, testing patterns
on our own channel
and then just repeating
what works over and
over again. And that
is how the Fairless
U Fast system works.
So now let's move
on to the next
video. I'm going to
show you how to
do all of this.
See you then. Thanks
for watching. I hope
you enjoyed this in
depth.